
Nmap Scan Analysis  

   Overview  
This document outlines the process and observations of a simple   Nmap   scan conducted for network analysis. Additionally,   Wireshark   was used to track packet flow during the scan.  

   Scan Procedure  
    Step 1: Open Nmap  
Launch   Nmap   to begin the scanning process.  

    Step 2: Open Terminal  
Access the terminal on your system to enter scanning commands.  

    Step 3: Execute Basic Scan  
Run the following command for a   SYN scan  :  

use 
nmap  sS [IP Address]  
     

This performs a stealthy SYN scan on the target system.  

    Step 4: Advanced Scanning Options  
To refine results, additional   flags   can be used:  

    Aggressive Scan  :   A  (Provides OS detection, version detection, and traceroute)  
    OS Scan  :   O  (Attempts to determine the operating system)  
    Service Scan  :   sV  (Identifies versions of running services)  
    IPv6 Scan  :   6  (Scans IPv6 addresses)  
    
	I have used Verbose (-v) for more information

    Step 5: Packet Analysis with Wireshark  
Wireshark was used to track packets exchanged during the scan. Despite multiple approaches, no open ports were detected on the local network—meaning no services like   SSH, HTTP, or HTTPS   were accessible.  

   Ethical Considerations  
  The scan was   NOT   conducted on unauthorized systems.  
    Scanme.org   was used as a test target.  
  IPv6 address retrieval proved   unsuccessful  , reinforcing ethical boundaries for scanning external networks.  

Conclusion  
The scan confirmed that the tested network did not expose open ports. Wireshark provided valuable insights into packet behavior but did not uncover vulnerable services.  
